<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <!-- 
        METADATA 
        These fields are used for the header and search indexing.
    -->
    <title>Is Transsexuality a Sin?</title>
    <author>Evan Minich</author>

    <!-- 
        TAGS 
        These are used for the "Advanced Filter" feature on the landing page.
        Each tag should be wrapped in a <tag> element.
    -->
    <tags>
        <tag>Sin</tag>
    </tags>

    <!-- 
        BODY CONTENT
        The main text of the article. Use multiple <paragraph> tags.
        Bible references (e.g., Ephesians 2:8-9) written here are automatically
        detected and hyperlinked by the website.
    -->
    <body>
        <paragraph>
            Gender disphoria and social conformity are the leading causes of transsexuality in our culture today. Many individuals who struggle with their sexual identity resort to altering their body and/or behavior to reflect that of the opposite sex. While gender dysphoria is a real psychological condition and is not a sin per se, the sin of transsexuality originates from one's desire to substitute the body God gave them for that which does not reflect His intended design (Jeremiah 1:5).
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            The Bible does not specifically address transsexuality, but it does provide principles that can be applied to this issue. God's original design for each person is necessarily perfect. To use an analogy, a person may be molded to be a wrench: they are created to perform a specific function. If that person were to reject their design and attempt to function as a hammer, they could only hurt their body in an attempt to serve a different function than was intended. In the same way, when an individual rejects their God-given identity, they are attempting to function outside of God's perfect design, and will end up hurting themselves in seeking an identity outside what God intended (1 Corinthians 6:19-20, 1 Corinthians 6:18).
        </paragraph>
    </body>

    <!-- 
        SIDEBAR: RELATED ARTICLES
        Links to other XML files in your 'articles' folder.
        The 'slug' attribute should match the filename without the .xml extension.
        (e.g., slug="justification" links to justification.xml)
    -->
    <related>
        <item slug="is-homosexuality-a-sin"></item>
    </related>

    <!-- 
        SIDEBAR: REFERENCES
        External links and specific Bible citations for the sidebar list.
        <link>: Creates an external hyperlink (requires 'url' attribute).
        <bible>: Creates a link to BibleGateway (no URL needed, just text).
    -->
    <references>
        <link url="https://answersingenesis.org/family/marriage/paganism-and-the-transexual-revolution/">Paganism and the Transsexual Revolution</link>
    </references>
</article>